<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments on Portfolio website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignments on Portfolio website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.143.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 11:09:52 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>05 Design Work &amp; Critical Making</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/05-design-work-critical-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 11:09:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/05-design-work-critical-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-5-reflective-questions&#34;&gt;Week 5 Reflective Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;knowledge-resulting-from-tinkering&#34;&gt;Knowledge resulting from tinkering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The knowledge resulting from tinkering in my experience is mostly problem solving skills and creativity. You are constantly focussing on how things fit together and can be changed. It also has big impact on being scared to try stuff out, you are constantly doing things and mostly exploring with your hands which removes this anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tinkering-with-digital-and-electronic-media&#34;&gt;Tinkering with digital and electronic media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinkering with digital and electronic media adds some form of interaction since often sensors or microcontrollers are used which are able to provide some form of feedback. It also combines the physical world with the computing world to create something. Coding is also open-ended however there are some rules or syntax which must be used in order to get it working.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Facilitation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/03-facilitation2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 11:09:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/03-facilitation2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-3-reflective-questions&#34;&gt;Week 3 Reflective Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lego-serious-play&#34;&gt;LEGO Serious Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;role-of-adults-in-facilitation&#34;&gt;Role of Adults in Facilitation?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children are often used to just starting to play and seeing what is happening especially with LEGO. Adults might need more encouragement to start, be creative and keep going assuring them that they can not do something wrong. Adults have not played in a long time so some start up time shoiuld also be kept in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;relevant-concepts&#34;&gt;Relevant Concepts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on: using your hands to express your thoughts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metaphors: expressing ideas with metaphors that can be found in the LEGO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing &amp;amp; Safety: making sure people speak up and listen to what others say in a safe, non-judgmental environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-papert--montessori&#34;&gt;Teaching: Papert &amp;amp; Montessori&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Invent to Learn book chapter 5 multiple key principles by Papert and Montessori can be identified.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Hands-on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/02-hands-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 11:09:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/02-hands-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-2-reflective-questions&#34;&gt;Week 2 Reflective Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not physically present during session two and received some information from peers but that was not very useful. I looked into the concept of Affordance and searched for all the different materials online to make the material table. The table can be found on the material table tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of affordance is used to give a better understanding about what makes materials good for tinkering. The concept of affordance can be viewed from two perspectives, namely Gibson and Norman. Gibson is focussed on the ecological psychology [1] and Norman used the human-computer interaction (HCI) framework [2].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 Getting Started</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/assignments/01-getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 11:09:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/assignments/01-getting_started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-1-reflective-questions&#34;&gt;Week 1 Reflective Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-page&#34;&gt;About Page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now find information about me in the about tab!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workspace&#34;&gt;Workspace&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below you can find a picture of my own workspace!
&lt;img alt=&#34;Workspace desk&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/Bureau.JPEG&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Workspace storage&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/Kast.JPEG&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my workspace I have a lot of different materials and tools which I am able to use, these are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3D printer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wood tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hammer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screwdrivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lego&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sewing kit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino kit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronic parts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sketchbooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pencils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brushes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tinker the most in the Design domain more specific in the electronics and 3D printing domains. In these domains the tinkering helps to create prototypes and also iterate these prototypes to see in what ways a prototype can be made and what can be changed. After that the tinkering helps to combine all of these prototypes into one main idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
